Jule Berry

julecberry@gmail.com linkedin.com/juleberry | github.com/juleberry

A results-oriented professional with 10+ years of experience in retail, management, nail technology, and web design. Seeking a career change to a software engineering role where I can use my tech skills, customer service experience, and problem-solving ability to work for an established organization in the tech field.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

[Nail Salon], Virginia

2017 - Present

Licensed Nail Technician

 Providing clients with unique natural nail services that includes developing easy-to-follow nail care regimens to ensure long term nail health.

OMNI Interactions, Colorado (remote)

2020 - 2021

Email Customer Support Representative

- Resolved customer inquiries/complaints about missing funds utilizing multiple digital software systems to track customer payments for reimbursement.
- Managed multiple accounts to serve as liaison for technical support to customers.

Brown's Hyundai, Virginia

2015 - 2017

Receptionist

 Devised plan to secure keys from inventory decreasing the loss of keys which increased used car sales profits by at least \$300 per sale

Hope's Treasures, Virginia

2013 - 2015

Assistant Store Manager

 Implemented major overhaul of store layout to increase store visibility and decrease theft of merchandise.

Best Buy, Virginia

2007 - 2012

Best Buy Mobile Sales Associate

- Troubleshooting issues with mobile devices and cellular connectivity to decrease returns of devices
- Evaluated devices and processed warranty repair service claims based on findings

Customer Solutions Specialist

- Resolved customer inquiries about product issues thus decreasing product returns.
- Served as store representative during rollout of new point of sales software and trained all employees on company software to increase the close of sales.

PROJECTS

Red River, Washington, DC

February 2021 (1 Month Project)

Desktop Support Engineer

 Re-configured workstations involved in cyberattack and re-installed required client software to recover digital operations at a hospital location.

EDUCATION

Per Scholas SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, Washington, DC

November 2022

Certifications: Software Engineering (2022)

freeCodeCamp, (Online, Self Paced)

May 2022

Certifications: Responsive Web Design

Colorado Technical University, (Online)

April 2019 - June 2019

Relevant Coursework: Problem Solving in Computer Science; Fundamentals of Networking

SKILLS

Soft: Adaptable, coachable, communicator, detail-oriented, empathetic, problem-solver

Technical: CSS, Express, HTML, JavaScript, Mongoose, MongoDB Atlas, NodeJS, React, Version Control

INTERESTS

Genealogy Research, League Bowling, Crafting